The mission begins.
Mission: Impossible III is a adventure, action,
thriller film directed by J.J. Abrams.
Retired from active duty, and training recruits for the Impossible Mission Force, agent Ethan Hunt faces the toughest foe of
his career: Owen Davian, an international broker of arms and information, who's as cunning as he is ruthless.
Davian emerges to threaten Hunt and all that he holds
dear – including the woman Hunt loves.
Ethan Hunt, played by Tom Cruise.
Owen Davian, played by Philip Seymour Hoffman.
Luther, played by Ving Rhames.
Musgrave, played by Billy Crudup.
Julia, played by Michelle Monaghan.
Declan, played by Jonathan Rhys Meyers.
Mission: Impossible III (abbreviated as M:i:III) is a 2006
American action spy film directed by J.
Abrams (in his feature film directorial debut), and produced by and starring Tom Cruise, from a
screenplay by Abrams and the writing team of Alex Kurtzman and Roberto Orci.
It is a standalone sequel to Mission: Impossible (1996) and Mission: Impossible 2
(2000) and the third installment in the Mission: Impossible film series.
It also stars Philip Seymour Hoffman, Ving Rhames, Billy Crudup, Michelle Monaghan,
Jonathan Rhys Meyers, Keri Russell, Maggie Q and Laurence Fishburne.
In Mission: Impossible III, retired Impossible Mission Force (IMF) agent and trainer Ethan Hunt (Cruise)
is forced to return to active duty to capture elusive arms dealer Owen Davian (Hoffman).
Development for a third Mission: Impossible film began in 2002, with David Fincher slated to direct; he and
his eventual replacement Joe Carnahan both departed by 2004, both citing creative differences.
Abrams was hired months later at the behest of Cruise, who was a fan of Abrams's Alias (2001–2006), but this further delayed production on the film due to Abrams's contractual
obligations for Alias and Lost (2004–2010), and caused prospective cast additions Kenneth Branagh, Carrie-Anne Moss and Scarlett Johansson to depart the film.
Principal photography began in July 2005 and lasted until that November, with filming
locations including Shanghai, Berlin, Rome, Los Angeles and Vatican City.
Mission: Impossible III premiered at the Tribeca Film Festival on April 26, 2006, and
was released in the United States by Paramount Pictures on May 5, 2006.
It received generally positive reviews from critics, with praise for its pace and
stunts, and was considered an improvement over its predecessors.
The film grossed over $398 million worldwide, becoming the eighth-highest-grossing
film of 2006, but became the lowest-grossing film in the franchise.
The sequel, Ghost Protocol, was released in 2011.
The film's storylines are continued by future sequels
Fallout (2018) and The Final Reckoning (2025).
The film explores themes of mask, mission, berlin, germany,
central intelligence agency (cia), computer.
The tone is lighthearted and intense.